<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.0.3">Jekyll</generator>
<link href="http://localhost:3000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
<link href="http://localhost:3000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
<updated>2016-08-25T15:31:54-06:00</updated>
<id>http://localhost:3000/</id>
<title>Yifan Chen</title>
<entry>
<title>苹果玩游戏</title>
<link href="http://localhost:3000/%E8%8B%B9%E6%9E%9C%E7%8E%A9%E6%B8%B8%E6%88%8F/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="苹果玩游戏" />
<published>2016-08-25T00:00:00-06:00</published>
<updated>2016-08-25T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
<id>http://localhost:3000/苹果玩游戏</id>
<content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:3000/%E8%8B%B9%E6%9E%9C%E7%8E%A9%E6%B8%B8%E6%88%8F/">&lt;p&gt;貌似很多人对Mac电脑打游戏有误区，我来科普一下。大家都明白，显卡的好坏直接影响到游戏的效果。其实，显卡只是硬件方面对游戏产生的影响。软件方面，也同样重要。我们平常所说的Mac不是用来打游戏的里面包含的就是这两个部分，显卡和图形API。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;我们今天主要讨论一下图形API对游戏的影响，至于显卡硬件，仁者见仁。改天讨论。首先， 我们来 解释一下为什么图形API会对游戏产生影响。一个不恰当的例子，如果你有一个上等的食材（显卡），不经过加工（图形API），你也无法感受到食材的味道（游戏效果）。其实就是这么简单，只有显卡和图形API同时好的情况下，游戏效果才会格外给力。如果只有好的显卡而没有好的图形API, 就是有力使不出，郁闷到不行。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;然后，我们来总结一下市面上现有的图形API。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;DirectX: 微软的自己技术，并没有开源，所以微软自己一直在用。&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;OpenGL: 一个很老的图形API，霸占市场多年，除了微软，其他都在用它。&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Vulkan：一个比较新技术，  支持Android, Windows和Linux。&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Metal: 苹果自己的技术，已经被应用在iOS和macOS上面了。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;directx&quot;&gt;DirectX&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;这个是微软自己的技术，没有开源，不花太多时间来讲，不然跑题了。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;opengl&quot;&gt;OpenGL&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://u.yablyk.com/2014/06/metal-vs-opengl.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OpenGL是Silicon Graphics的技术，在业内也算是比较臭名昭著了。简单来说，他们不思进取，不求创新，很多游戏厂商，还有科技公司都合作的不开心。同样的，在苹果没有自己的技术之前，不得不用OpenGL，然后由于OpenGL在开发，算法上面很落后，各种夹层让游戏开发商和显卡制造商没法优化，从而达不到应有的游戏效果。当然，OpenGL这种无节操做法的后果就是，各个公司不跟你玩儿了，都开始开发自己图形API技术。所以，OpenGL骚不了多久了。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;vulkan&quot;&gt;Vulkan&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vulkan可以说是一个全新的图形API技术，貌似谷歌也是受够了OpenGL在各方面的限制。谷歌在今年的I/O上面就很器重的使用了Vulkan在自己的VR Daydream上面，已经开始鼓励开发者使用Vulkan。抛弃OpenGL只是时间问题了。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;metal&quot;&gt;Metal&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://photos.appleinsidercdn.com/gallery/13162-7625-0e2d339400c1558dbad535dfd598b1639f2ee76a_large_2x-l.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Metal是苹果自己的图形API，是在WWDC 2014上面介绍给iOS的，在WWDC 2015上面又公布了会来macOS的好消息。 根据苹果介绍Metal可以有效的把游戏的画面提升一半以上。最好的例子就是，现在所有在iOS上面玩的游戏都是用Meal开发的。拿起来和Android比较的话，有过之而无不及。这里就不提Windows了，你懂的。当然，更令人开心的是，Metal已经在El Captain上面蓄势待发中。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.apple.com/live/2015-june-event/images/f898e89b684ed1ca8cc34d76ddf23e2c8fced224_expanded_medium.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;那么我们现在知道图形API对游戏有至关重要的作用，只要游戏开发者们愿意开发在Metal上面，Mac Gaming只是时间问题。更令人激动的是，暴雪《魔兽世界》Metal的内测版本已经发布了， 随后就是《风暴英雄》和《星际争霸》。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;好了，讲了这么多，基本就是想科普一下为什么Mac不是所谓的玩游戏的电脑。显卡的好坏只是最表面的一方面，软件也起了非常重要的作用。还是那句话，在这个颜值当道的年代，被忽略的往往是看不到的内涵。&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
<category term="Apple" />
<category term="Mac Gaming" />
<summary>貌似很多人对Mac电脑打游戏有误区，我来科普一下。大家都明白，显卡的好坏直接影响到游戏的效果。其实，显卡只是硬件方面对游戏产生的影响。软件方面，也同样重要。我们平常所说的Mac不是用来打游戏的里面包含的就是这两个部分，显卡和图形API。</summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title>英雄留下</title>
<link href="http://localhost:3000/%E8%8B%B1%E9%9B%84%E7%95%99%E4%B8%8B/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="英雄留下" />
<published>2016-08-14T00:00:00-06:00</published>
<updated>2016-08-14T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
<id>http://localhost:3000/英雄留下</id>
<content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:3000/%E8%8B%B1%E9%9B%84%E7%95%99%E4%B8%8B/">&lt;p&gt;激动的时刻，精彩的比赛，才华横溢的选手，有经历才有感动。中国电子竞技战队Wings在昨天《DOTA2》国际邀请赛的总决赛中以绝对的优势和精彩的比赛干沉了美国老牌强队DC。时隔一年再次让中国战队站在世界之巅，背后的付出和汗水不只是游戏玩得好这么简单。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;电子竞技一直是一个非常模糊的概念，到底算不算得上是体育，众说纷纭。直到2013年3月国家体育总局才决定成立国家队。即便如此，从很多层面上来讲，电竞选手依然没有得到与传统体育选手比肩的尊重。同样是为国争光，为什么会出现如此的局面 ，背后的价值观值得思考。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;说起电竞不得不谈《冰封王座》，这个《魔兽争霸3》的续作，当年在国内掀起的电竞风暴席卷各地。也许暴雪也不曾想到一款自己做的即时战略游戏能给小伙伴们带来如此值得回忆的青春。Sky的两度封王，Moon的冰火双重天，Grubby的世纪大战以及Sweet的绝世翻盘，一切一切的经典时刻，不单单是精彩比赛的呈现，而是她所承载的，我和小伙伴们的青春和友谊。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;后来《魔兽争霸3》的辉煌逐渐被更容易上手和商业模式更聪明的《DOTA2》和《英雄联盟》取代。虽然可惜，但是时代总是要进步的。只要是电子竞技，都会牵动着我们的心，看着国内电竞局面在一点一点的变好，曾经的那份痴情也算是得到了回报。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;我们玩魔兽那会儿，常说 “也许我们玩不了一辈子游戏，但是可以做一辈子朋友”，其中的无奈和心酸也只有经历过才到得出。而今天看到中国战队能在电子竞技的世界舞台上这样辉煌，也算满足了当年我们那帮追风少年没有完成的梦想，当他们把五星红旗带到领奖台的最高处时，一句荡气回肠的“英雄留下”是我们对他们最好的祝福。&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
<category term="gaming" />
<category term="thoughts" />
<category term="esports" />
<summary>激动的时刻，精彩的比赛，才华横溢的选手，有经历才有感动。中国电子竞技战队Wings在昨天《DOTA2》国际邀请赛的总决赛中以绝对的优势和精彩的比赛干沉了美国老牌强队DC。时隔一年再次让中国战队站在世界之巅，背后的付出和汗水不只是游戏玩得好这么简单。</summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title>河东河西</title>
<link href="http://localhost:3000/river-east-river-west/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="河东河西" />
<published>2016-07-31T00:00:00-06:00</published>
<updated>2016-07-31T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
<id>http://localhost:3000/river-east-river-west</id>
<content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:3000/river-east-river-west/">&lt;p&gt;华为和小米相继出笔记本了，虽然手机到电脑算不上行业的跨度，但是其目的不仅仅是瓜分电脑市场这么简单，背后的野心更是让人眼前一亮。纵观国内日益强大的科技业，产品丰富且个性化，非常令人期待看到未来几年中国科技业对世界科技圈的冲击。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;乔布斯说过，日本人很善于做精巧的小玩意儿。从索尼早期标志性的产品Walkman, 任天堂的Gameboy到后来的各种品牌CD机，日本品牌在小型电子产品上的造诣绝对是垄断级别的。 而索尼这个在全球拥有众多粉丝的日本品牌在无论是在企业管理，品牌运营以及工业设计上面都让乔布斯折服。今天，索尼年年亏损，不得不放弃各种业务来保留那一份最后的情怀。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;雅虎这个当年市值高达260亿美元的门户网站也不得不面对今天被贱卖的尴尬局面。保守的策略让公司错过很多再续辉煌的机会，留下的只是遗憾。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;诺基亚的情况更糟糕，如果说被微软收购是诺基亚最后的救命稻草，那么微软放弃手机业务的策略更是把诺基亚达打到了一个站不起来的位置。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;三个世界级的品牌，三个不同的国家。在光阴的印证下，留下的是辉煌的业绩和抹不去的历史。与此同时，新生的科技生命正在成为时代的主角。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;常言道，三十年河东，三十年河西。&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
<category term="technologies" />
<category term="thoughts" />
<summary>华为和小米相继出笔记本了，虽然手机到电脑算不上行业的跨度，但是其目的不仅仅是瓜分电脑市场这么简单，背后的野心更是让人眼前一亮。纵观国内日益强大的科技业，产品丰富且个性化，非常令人期待看到未来几年中国科技业对世界科技圈的冲击。</summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title>Thoughts of Three Days Conference at Downtown San Francisco</title>
<link href="http://localhost:3000/thoughts-of-three-days-conference/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Thoughts of Three Days Conference at Downtown San Francisco" />
<published>2016-07-30T00:00:00-06:00</published>
<updated>2016-07-30T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
<id>http://localhost:3000/thoughts-of-three-days-conference</id>
<content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:3000/thoughts-of-three-days-conference/">&lt;p&gt;I spent three days in downtown San Francisco for ForwardJS Conference this week. It has been fun, attending the conference is the purpose of the trip. Immersing in the city is a bonus to the plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been in southern California many times, but San Francisco was my first stop in the north. The weather gets chilly in the mornings and nights. Some areas can be foggy at sunset. Daytime temperature is a lot warmer than mornings and nights, so better have a jacket handy. If I don’t happen to be a summer animal, I would like the weather more. I was glad I checked the weather before, so I took a jacket with me, it was not useless at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, workshops can be ruined by not prepare materials before. The intentions of attending workshops are getting trained for certain things you don’t know, or you barely know. We are developers, so obviously, we don’t want to come out with a “Hello, World!” application after training. But, workshop goes faster, the best way to get the most out of it is knowing the content. For the best, build something before you go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another way to ruin workshops is from instructors. Having few hours long presentations regarding history, benefits and future of the content. That is wrong. I am not saying that I don’t value any of that. But, it’s a workshop, hands down and build.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion,  not every workshop is worth the energy to go. For those of you who thinks one workshop can get you up to speed, you are wrong. You might be able to build something, but won’t be able to understand everything. To master something, it takes serious dedication and motivation.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
<category term="conference" />
<category term="thoughts" />
<summary>I spent three days in downtown San Francisco for ForwardJS Conference this week. It has been fun, attending the conference is the purpose of the trip. Immersing in the city is a bonus to the plan.</summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title>Thoughts of Using Vim</title>
<link href="http://localhost:3000/thoughts-of-using-vim/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Thoughts of Using Vim" />
<published>2016-07-20T00:00:00-06:00</published>
<updated>2016-07-20T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
<id>http://localhost:3000/thoughts-of-using-vim</id>
<content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:3000/thoughts-of-using-vim/">&lt;p&gt;I installed &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jceb/vim-orgmode&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;vim-orgmode&lt;/a&gt; to my Vim yesterday. For those of you, who haven’t heard Org-mode, it is an editing and organizing mode for notes, planning, and authoring in Emacs. It is a must have for all Emacs users. I strongly recommend you to watch &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oJTwQvgfgMM&quot;&gt;this video&lt;/a&gt; on youtube. It will mostly likely change your view of how powerful something can be. Due to Org-mode’s popularity, someone awesome created a orgmode for vim on Github. I found it and installed it. Thanks for the open source community, life is beautiful because of you. I like Vim as a text editor, like Emacs as an environment(no offense to Emacs users, I honestly think Emacs is too powerful to be a text editor).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took a little time go through my &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/yifanchen/dotfiles/blob/master/.vimrc&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;.vimrc&lt;/a&gt; file after I committed the change to Github, it then occurred to me that Vim has been so much fun to use for the past eight months. And, learning Vim has been a tremendous investment to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have always preferred videos when it comes to learning. Having some kinds of visual presentations can get me through the points a lot easier. So, Youtube is my best friend. But, there weren’t many Vim tutorials on Youtube. I had to find other ways to learn. Lots people write blogs of their dotfiles. Those were helpful If I only wanted their Vim settings. Vim wiki is a good place to go, but too dry to read. I didn’t have many options left, but being patient, learning it slowly. I ended up spending weeks figuring out every piece of vimscript that I need. I tried to make Vim behave like a regular IDE. I had easy options like using Vim GUI or installing Vim emulators in standard text editors. I tried vim-mode package in Atom, and it was flawless. However, I wasn’t too satisfied with it. I didn’t quite like running both Atom and iTerm while doing development. I distinctly remember I talked myself out of using Atom with vim-mode not one time, not twice, but multiple times just because the nerdy soul in me didn’t allow me to go with the simple choice. You know, sometimes being stubborn is a double edge, I guess in my case, at least this time it was on the right side. I made it happen, the UI, the speed, and the capabilities of my Vim are not as same as a standard editor, but unique and better.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
<category term="Vim" />
<category term="thoughts" />
<summary>I installed vim-orgmode to my Vim yesterday. For those of you, who haven’t heard Org-mode, it is an editing and organizing mode for notes, planning, and authoring in Emacs. It is a must have for all Emacs users. I strongly recommend you to watch this video on youtube. It will mostly likely change your view of how powerful something can be. Due to Org-mode’s popularity, someone awesome created a orgmode for vim on Github. I found it and installed it. Thanks for the open source community, life is beautiful because of you. I like Vim as a text editor, like Emacs as an environment(no offense to Emacs users, I honestly think Emacs is too powerful to be a text editor).</summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title>Progressive Web App</title>
<link href="http://localhost:3000/progressive-web-app/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Progressive Web App" />
<published>2016-07-12T00:00:00-06:00</published>
<updated>2016-07-12T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
<id>http://localhost:3000/progressive-web-app</id>
<content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:3000/progressive-web-app/">
</content>
<category term="Projects" />
<category term="Progressive Web App" />
</entry>
<entry>
<title>Node Server</title>
<link href="http://localhost:3000/node-server/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Node Server" />
<published>2016-07-09T00:00:00-06:00</published>
<updated>2016-07-09T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
<id>http://localhost:3000/node-server</id>
<content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:3000/node-server/">
</content>
<category term="Projects" />
<category term="Node" />
</entry>
<entry>
<title>Reduxstagram</title>
<link href="http://localhost:3000/reduxgram/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Reduxstagram" />
<published>2016-07-06T00:00:00-06:00</published>
<updated>2016-07-06T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
<id>http://localhost:3000/reduxgram</id>
<content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:3000/reduxgram/">
</content>
<category term="Projects" />
<category term="Redux" />
<category term="React" />
</entry>
<entry>
<title>奔跑吧，魔兽骚年</title>
<link href="http://localhost:3000/warcraft-boy/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="奔跑吧，魔兽骚年" />
<published>2016-07-05T00:00:00-06:00</published>
<updated>2016-07-05T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
<id>http://localhost:3000/warcraft-boy</id>
<content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:3000/warcraft-boy/">&lt;p&gt;正在写…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-本文纪念我和小伙伴们那逝去的青春。&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
<category term="story" />
<category term="魔兽骚年" />
<summary>正在写…</summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title>Today is a Present</title>
<link href="http://localhost:3000/today-is-present/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Today is a Present" />
<published>2016-07-04T00:00:00-06:00</published>
<updated>2016-07-04T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
<id>http://localhost:3000/today-is-present</id>
<content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:3000/today-is-present/">&lt;p&gt;I recently gave a short talk to few iOS development students who are currently in Code Camp busting their asses to finish projects. I am very proud of them. Decisions were not easy to make when they wanted to change careers, especially when some of them have families. Most students ditched their no-future careers, then entirely dedicated to intensive Code Camp courses, hopefully, coming out with great skill sets to find jobs that they like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I heard that a lot of people say coding is easier than it looks, I disagree, coding is not easy at all, in fact, it is hard from lots different aspects. I learned to code in a hard way. It was my sophomore year in college. I was introduced to web programming, precisely HTML and CSS. I could barely follow class speed, and everything professor taught in class was like some irrelevant information, it got into my head, but not my brain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I started to learn JavaScript, it was worse. I didn’t understand anything, literally anything. No matter how long I spent, no matter how many times I translated study material into my native language, I just couldn’t wrap my head around of those programming terms. I read books without any comprehension.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have never been one of those smart students in class, and I probably will never be. But, that’s okay. To make things happen, I don’t have to be super smart or talented as long as I work hard and willing to improve. There are millions of code snippets out there I can grab if I can’t write my own,  at least I know that I can manipulate them to the way I need. If one code snippet doesn’t work, I will try a different one until I find the one it does. I believe as time goes, I am going to be
good at what I am doing, all I need is persistence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People tend to say no to new things. It is a Human Nature. You feel vulnerable when you learn, nobody likes that feeling. However, look at the bright side, whenever you are feeling vulnerable, it means you are learning, feeling weak is just the first step of becoming better. The thing is you have to believe in yourself and invest yourself. People often say that if you don’t even believe in yourself, why should anyone else?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, to make this blog post wise. I’d like to quote from Master Oogway, &lt;em&gt;Don’t be too concerned with what was and what will be. There’s a saying, yesterday is a history, tomorrow is a mystery, today is a gift, that is why it’s called present.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
<category term="thought" />
<summary>I recently gave a short talk to few iOS development students who are currently in Code Camp busting their asses to finish projects. I am very proud of them. Decisions were not easy to make when they wanted to change careers, especially when some of them have families. Most students ditched their no-future careers, then entirely dedicated to intensive Code Camp courses, hopefully, coming out with great skill sets to find jobs that they like.</summary>
</entry>
</feed>
