<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.0.3">Jekyll</generator>
<link href="http://localhost:3000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
<link href="http://localhost:3000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
<updated>2016-07-11T17:26:44-06:00</updated>
<id>http://localhost:3000/</id>
<title>Yifan Chen</title>
<entry>
<title>Reduxstagram</title>
<link href="http://localhost:3000/reduxgram/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Reduxstagram" />
<published>2016-07-06T00:00:00-06:00</published>
<updated>2016-07-06T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
<id>http://localhost:3000/reduxgram</id>
<content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:3000/reduxgram/">
</content>
<category term="Projects" />
<category term="Redux" />
<category term="React" />
</entry>
<entry>
<title>奔跑吧，魔兽骚年</title>
<link href="http://localhost:3000/warcraft-boy/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="奔跑吧，魔兽骚年" />
<published>2016-07-05T00:00:00-06:00</published>
<updated>2016-07-05T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
<id>http://localhost:3000/warcraft-boy</id>
<content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:3000/warcraft-boy/">&lt;p&gt;正在写…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-本文纪念我和小伙伴们那逝去的青春。&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
<category term="story" />
<category term="魔兽骚年" />
<summary>正在写…</summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title>Today is a Present</title>
<link href="http://localhost:3000/today-is-present/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Today is a Present" />
<published>2016-07-04T00:00:00-06:00</published>
<updated>2016-07-04T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
<id>http://localhost:3000/today-is-present</id>
<content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:3000/today-is-present/">&lt;p&gt;I recently gave a short talk to few iOS development students who are currently in Code Camp busting their asses to finish projects. I am very proud of them. Decisions were not easy to make when they wanted to change careers, especially when some of them have families. Most students ditched their no-future careers, then entirely dedicated to intensive Code Camp courses, hopefully, coming out with great skill sets to find jobs that they like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I heard that a lot of people say coding is easier than it looks, I disagree, coding is not easy at all, in fact, it is hard from lots different aspects. I learned to code in a hard way. It was my sophomore year in college. I was introduced to web programming, precisely HTML and CSS. I could barely follow class speed, and everything professor taught in class was like some irrelevant information, it got into my head, but not my brain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I started to learn JavaScript, it was worse. I didn’t’ understand anything, literally anything. No matter how long I spent, no matter how many times I translated study material into my native language, I just couldn’t wrap my head around of those programming terms. I read books without any comprehension.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have never been one of those smart students in class, and I probably will never be. But, that’s okay. To make things happen, I don’t have to be super smart or talented as long as I work hard and willing to improve. There are millions of code snippets out there I can grab if I can’t write my own,  at least I know that I can manipulate them to the way I need. If one code snippet doesn’t work, I will try a different one until I find the one it does. I believe as time goes, I am going to be
good at what I am doing, all I need is persistence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People tend to say no to new things. It is a Human Nature. You feel vulnerable when you learn, nobody likes that feeling. However, look at the bright side, whenever you are feeling vulnerable, it means you are learning, feeling weak is just the first step of becoming better. The thing is you have to believe in yourself and invest yourself. People often say that if you don’t even believe in yourself, why should anyone else?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, to make this blog post wise. I’d like to quote from Master Oogway, &lt;em&gt;Don’t be too concerned with what was and what will be. There’s a saying, yesterday is a history, tomorrow is a mystery, today is a gift, that is why it’s called present.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
<category term="thought" />
<summary>I recently gave a short talk to few iOS development students who are currently in Code Camp busting their asses to finish projects. I am very proud of them. Decisions were not easy to make when they wanted to change careers, especially when some of them have families. Most students ditched their no-future careers, then entirely dedicated to intensive Code Camp courses, hopefully, coming out with great skill sets to find jobs that they like.</summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title>不变的范特西</title>
<link href="http://localhost:3000/still-fantasy/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="不变的范特西" />
<published>2016-06-30T00:00:00-06:00</published>
<updated>2016-06-30T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
<id>http://localhost:3000/still-fantasy</id>
<content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:3000/still-fantasy/">&lt;p&gt;印象里，我只花过一次钱买歌曲专辑 。12岁那年，我在购书。店里的背景音乐是《爱在西元前》，我当时觉得歌曲节奏轻快，旋律性强，歌词虽听不太清，但不影响我对歌曲的喜爱，于是买了一盘《范特西》回家，那是我第一次花钱买歌曲专辑。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;一年之后，当西方人民都在恐慌五角大楼打飞机的同时，地球的另一端，我哼着《双截棍》顺利考入城内一所二流初中。家长和老师眼里除了读书还是读书的学生生活单调到不行，好像所有的课余生活就剩听歌，大街小巷的《东风破》，仿佛世界都在放中国风。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;步入高中，我对学习彻底失去了兴趣，辗转几个学校也没起到任何作用。父母郁闷的同时，无知的我天天在听《七里香》，17岁的夏天，美好到不行，满怀期待自己初恋的到来。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;穿越太平洋，美利坚不相信眼泪。语言的不同和文化的差异对一个不经世事的19岁少年来说相当残酷。伴随的，依旧是音乐，对家的思念让我爱上《听妈妈的话》。努力天天向上的同时，《一路向北》支持着我前进。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;上班之后，在线音乐服务是主流，世界级的音乐可供选择时候，不变的是那个叫“范特西” 的播放目录，里面的歌曲只加不减。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;犹记那年，我买了一盘叫《范特西》的磁带回家，那是我最后一次花钱买歌曲专辑，拉开的，是丰富的人生序幕。&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
<category term="Jay Chou" />
<category term="Music" />
<category term="thoughts" />
<summary>印象里，我只花过一次钱买歌曲专辑 。12岁那年，我在购书。店里的背景音乐是《爱在西元前》，我当时觉得歌曲节奏轻快，旋律性强，歌词虽听不太清，但不影响我对歌曲的喜爱，于是买了一盘《范特西》回家，那是我第一次花钱买歌曲专辑。</summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title>React Start Kit</title>
<link href="http://localhost:3000/React-Startkit/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="React Start Kit" />
<published>2016-06-23T00:00:00-06:00</published>
<updated>2016-06-23T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
<id>http://localhost:3000/React-Startkit</id>
<content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:3000/React-Startkit/">
</content>
<category term="React" />
</entry>
<entry>
<title>React Interactive Menu</title>
<link href="http://localhost:3000/react-menu/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="React Interactive Menu" />
<published>2016-06-20T00:00:00-06:00</published>
<updated>2016-06-20T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
<id>http://localhost:3000/react-menu</id>
<content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:3000/react-menu/">
</content>
<category term="React" />
</entry>
<entry>
<title>WWDC 2016</title>
<link href="http://localhost:3000/WWDC-2016/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="WWDC 2016" />
<published>2016-06-14T00:00:00-06:00</published>
<updated>2016-06-14T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
<id>http://localhost:3000/WWDC-2016</id>
<content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:3000/WWDC-2016/">&lt;p&gt;There are too many articles are talking about what you need to know from yesterday’s Keynote. I am not going to summarize it again. I admitted that I wanted a new MBP more than anything. Believe me, I impatiently waited for the whole time for Tim Cook to say &lt;em&gt;One More Thing&lt;/em&gt;, damn it, it didn’t happen. With a mindset like that, I still liked Keynote, because it meant a brand new chapter to both consumers and developers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple indeed comprised its ego, opened SDKs of its key applications to developers on four platforms. It grants advanced authorities to developers to build applications in a much more flexible way. In another word, Apple no longer asks developers to create what Apple wants. Instead, developers can be a lot more creative with what they want and what people wants. With the significant upcoming changes on iOS 10, apparently, Apple compromises to a fact of what people wants. It’s opposed to Jobs’ famous quote - &lt;em&gt;A lot of times, people don’t know what they want until you show it to them&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, I liked the Keynote. I am excited to see how Apple’s products will turn out after its compromise.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
<category term="wwdc 2016" />
<category term="Technology" />
<summary>There are too many articles are talking about what you need to know from yesterday’s Keynote. I am not going to summarize it again. I admitted that I wanted a new MBP more than anything. Believe me, I impatiently waited for the whole time for Tim Cook to say One More Thing, damn it, it didn’t happen. With a mindset like that, I still liked Keynote, because it meant a brand new chapter to both consumers and developers.</summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title>论性格的重要性</title>
<link href="http://localhost:3000/extrovert-personality/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="论性格的重要性" />
<published>2016-06-05T00:00:00-06:00</published>
<updated>2016-06-05T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
<id>http://localhost:3000/extrovert-personality</id>
<content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:3000/extrovert-personality/">&lt;p&gt;锤子科技是个不错的公司，罗永浩这个当年的愤青现在的企业家其实很适合做科技，所谓性格使然。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;不久之前看《鲁豫有约》邀请罗永浩，老罗的很多观点不错，对自己过去的错误以及公司未来的把握也很明确。老罗有强迫症，寻求完美的同时，必定严苛要求员工，也许是个难相处的CEO，换来的却是精益求精的产品。貌似由于他刚开始做锤子科技的时候，性格比较尖，口无遮拦，导致公司被很多人黑。其实完全没有这个必要，如果不喜欢一个CEO，没有必要去黑他的公司。性格的缺陷往往成就了非凡的创造力。而创造力，则是今天国内大多科技公司最缺的资源。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;那么，罗永浩有个观点就是，同样能力的两个人外向性格比内向性格好混很多。我在工作上遇见过很多这样的情况。貌似很不公平，但是现实如此，只能适应。老话常谈，情商和智商需要协调。别以为你是“会跑的霍金”，谁都不鸟。我们都需要全面发展智商和情商。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;推荐本书《人性的弱点》，“人类出版史上的奇迹，20世纪以来最畅销的励志经典，永远不要奢望让世界来适应你，你对了，世界就对了。与人交往巾的“无形之手”，点拨你在社会中游刃有余。” 其实我更喜欢书的英文名字，《How to Win Friends and Influence People》，简单直白。&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
<category term="personality" />
<category term="thought" />
<summary>锤子科技是个不错的公司，罗永浩这个当年的愤青现在的企业家其实很适合做科技，所谓性格使然。</summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title>机器学习 • 人工智能 • 虚拟现实</title>
<link href="http://localhost:3000/machine-learning-and-ai/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="机器学习 • 人工智能 • 虚拟现实" />
<published>2016-06-02T00:00:00-06:00</published>
<updated>2016-06-02T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
<id>http://localhost:3000/machine-learning-and-ai</id>
<content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:3000/machine-learning-and-ai/">&lt;p&gt;机器学习，人工智能， 虚拟现实绝对是当下科技行业最火的三个话题。传统科技巨头们在这三个方面的投资已不是未知，回报颇丰。我觉得从发展前景，应用性和可塑造性几个方面来讲的话，虚拟现实目前还比不上机器学习和人工智能。所以，今天先不讨论虚拟现实（另外，苹果目前还没有虚拟现实的任何产品传闻，这太蹊跷，必有问题。所以，期待WWDC 2016）。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;机器学习是人工智能的核心，可以理解为，人工智能只是机器学习的一个单一方面。然而，机器学习又只是大数据的一个单一方面。有没有听过那句话，这是一个数据的年代？搞不好几百年后，会有个很火的游戏叫《数据时代》。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;谷歌是一个数据就是一切的公司，搜索引擎只是一个外在的不能再外在的表面。公司的模式是，通过整合用户搜索的数据和信息，扩展自己的产品模式，加以包装，再以免费的方式出售给用户来换取更多数据。可以这样理解，我们每一个人都是谷歌的产品，通过出售我们，拿下巨额广告费。不知不觉中，我们就作为产品被谷歌卖了。虽然感觉不爽，但是，谷歌作为目前市值最高的公司，在全方面融入我们生活的情况下，依然没有赚过我们一分钱（这个论点可能快说不通了， 毕竟谷歌也出了不少硬件。当然，主要收入还是广告）。所以，结论是：他很牛，让他随便卖吧。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;讲谷歌就是因为想讲他的机器学习和人工智能，毕竟做为这个星球上的科技老大，很多科技走向的标杆还是他来树立的。在今年的Google I/O上，谷歌毫无保留的秀了很多新科技，这些科技的背后支撑就是机器学习和人工智能。可以说，这是一个在机器学习以及人工智能领域的小进步，真正的把机器学习和人工智能带到了我们能看得见摸得到的面前。科技可以有很多种方式来服务用户，机器学习和人工智能很多时候的作用用户是感受不到的。比如过滤垃圾邮件，推荐电影或者歌曲，无线网络的无缝转换等等，这些是低调的呈现。又比如高调到爆的阿尔法狗，直接干沉李世石。前者和后者都是科技，只是呈现的方式不一样而已。 貌似前者来的更高端上档次点，所谓“好的科技是让人感受不到科技的存在”。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;差点讲跑题，总喜欢讲讲几个科技大佬之间的故事，看来需要下次从新讲。那么，机器学习和人工智能的未来在哪里？简单概括，很深很深。电影里面总喜欢讲人工智能有一天会反人类，这貌似离谱，却符合很多逻辑。人类往往重视外在而忽略内在。同样的道理，人工智能不需要一个物理机器人来做事情，当数据和软件在彻底渗入我们生活的每一刻的时候，威胁也在滋生。在硬件为软件服务的今天，其间隔小于零。也许，电影里面的很多非现实正在现实中靠近。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;当然，我们不能带有悲观的态度看问题，这样科技就不会进步了。一个不恰当的例子就是，如同汽车带来便利的同时，也有相当大的危险性。主要问题是需要一个相当完善并且持续更新的体系来预防可能发生一切。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;如果往今后几年看的话，很明显，大量机器学习和人工智能相关的工作会出现。最先出现的就是各种人工智能的助手， 语音是首打。这些助手会通过用户的资料和使用习惯来学习用户的日常所需，一点一点的变聪明，一点一点变好用，从而替代生活中的琐事。简单预测，将来语音助手会像手机一样和我们的生活密不可分。语音助手成熟之后，同步翻译还会远吗？&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;在不久的将来，大批的简单单一的工作会被人工智能取代，好处是高效率以及小于人类万分之一的犯错几率。人类的工作重心则会移到更加人性话的一面，比如，服务，设计，情感等方面的工作。不用担心就业不足的问题，随着时代改变应运而生的这个时代所需的新工作机会。然而，时代推动的则是科技的改变。最后，套用一句诺基亚的广告词，“科技，以人为本”。&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
<category term="machine learning" />
<category term="AI" />
<category term="VR" />
<summary>机器学习，人工智能， 虚拟现实绝对是当下科技行业最火的三个话题。传统科技巨头们在这三个方面的投资已不是未知，回报颇丰。我觉得从发展前景，应用性和可塑造性几个方面来讲的话，虚拟现实目前还比不上机器学习和人工智能。所以，今天先不讨论虚拟现实（另外，苹果目前还没有虚拟现实的任何产品传闻，这太蹊跷，必有问题。所以，期待WWDC 2016）。</summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title>Starting Machine Leanring</title>
<link href="http://localhost:3000/Machine-Learning/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Starting Machine Leanring" />
<published>2016-06-01T00:00:00-06:00</published>
<updated>2016-06-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
<id>http://localhost:3000/Machine-Learning</id>
<content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:3000/Machine-Learning/">
</content>
<category term="Projects" />
<category term="Machine Learning" />
</entry>
</feed>
