<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.0.3">Jekyll</generator>
<link href="http://localhost:3000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
<link href="http://localhost:3000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
<updated>2016-06-14T12:31:32-06:00</updated>
<id>http://localhost:3000/</id>
<title>Yifan Chen</title>
<entry>
<title>WWDC 2016</title>
<link href="http://localhost:3000/WWDC-2016/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="WWDC 2016" />
<published>2016-06-14T00:00:00-06:00</published>
<updated>2016-06-14T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
<id>http://localhost:3000/WWDC-2016</id>
<content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:3000/WWDC-2016/">&lt;p&gt;There are too many articles are talking about what you need to know from yesterday’s Keynote. I am not going to summarize it again. I admitted that I wanted a new MBP more than anything. Believe me, I impatiently waited for the whole time for Tim Cook to say &lt;em&gt;One More Thing&lt;/em&gt;, god damn it, it didn’t happen. With a mindset like that, I still liked Keynote, because it meant a brand new chapter to both consumers and developers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple indeed comprised its ego, opened SDKs of its key applications to developers on four platforms. It grants advanced authorities to developers to build applications in a much more flexible way. In another word, Apple no longer asks developers to create what Apple wants. Instead, developers can be a lot more creative with what they want and what people wants. With the significant upcoming changes on iOS 10, apparently, Apple compromises to a fact of what people wants. It’s opposed to Jobs’ famous quote &lt;em&gt;A lot of times, people don’t know what they want until you show it to them&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, I liked the Keynote. I am excited to see how Apple’s products will turn out after its compromise.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
<category term="wwdc 2016" />
<category term="Technology" />
<summary>There are too many articles are talking about what you need to know from yesterday’s Keynote. I am not going to summarize it again. I admitted that I wanted a new MBP more than anything. Believe me, I impatiently waited for the whole time for Tim Cook to say One More Thing, god damn it, it didn’t happen. With a mindset like that, I still liked Keynote, because it meant a brand new chapter to both consumers and developers.</summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title>论性格的重要性</title>
<link href="http://localhost:3000/extrovert-personality/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="论性格的重要性" />
<published>2016-06-05T00:00:00-06:00</published>
<updated>2016-06-05T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
<id>http://localhost:3000/extrovert-personality</id>
<content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:3000/extrovert-personality/">&lt;p&gt;锤子科技是个不错的公司，罗永浩这个当年的愤青现在的企业家其实很适合做科技，所谓性格使然。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;不久之前看《鲁豫有约》邀请罗永浩，老罗的很多观点不错，对自己过去的错误以及公司未来的把握也很明确。老罗有强迫症，寻求完美的同时，必定严苛要求员工，也许是个难相处的CEO，换来的却是精益求精的产品。貌似由于他刚开始做锤子科技的时候，性格比较尖，口无遮拦，导致公司被很多人黑。其实完全没有这个必要，如果不喜欢一个CEO，没有必要去黑他的公司。性格的缺陷往往成就了非凡的创造力。而创造力，则是今天国内大多科技公司最缺的资源。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;那么，罗永浩有个观点就是，同样能力的两个人外向性格比内向性格好混很多。我在工作上遇见过很多这样的情况。貌似很不公平，但是现实如此，只能适应。老话常谈，情商和智商需要协调。别以为你是“会跑的霍金”，谁都不鸟。我们都需要全面发展智商和情商。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;推荐本书《人性的弱点》，“人类出版史上的奇迹，20世纪以来最畅销的励志经典，永远不要奢望让世界来适应你，你对了，世界就对了。与人交往巾的“无形之手”，点拨你在社会中游刃有余。” 其实我更喜欢书的英文名字，《How to Win Friends and Influence People》，简单直白。&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
<category term="personality" />
<category term="thought" />
<summary>锤子科技是个不错的公司，罗永浩这个当年的愤青现在的企业家其实很适合做科技，所谓性格使然。</summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title>机器学习 • 人工智能 • 虚拟现实</title>
<link href="http://localhost:3000/machine-learning-and-ai/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="机器学习 • 人工智能 • 虚拟现实" />
<published>2016-06-02T00:00:00-06:00</published>
<updated>2016-06-02T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
<id>http://localhost:3000/machine-learning-and-ai</id>
<content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:3000/machine-learning-and-ai/">&lt;p&gt;机器学习，人工智能， 虚拟现实绝对是当下科技行业最火的三个话题。传统科技巨头们在这三个方面的投资已不是未知，回报颇丰。我觉得从发展前景，应用性和可塑造性几个方面来讲的话，虚拟现实目前还比不上机器学习和人工智能。所以，今天先不讨论虚拟现实（另外，苹果目前还没有虚拟现实的任何产品传闻，这太蹊跷，必有问题。所以，期待WWDC 2016）。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;机器学习是人工智能的核心，可以理解为，人工智能只是机器学习的一个单一方面。然而，机器学习又只是大数据的一个单一方面。有没有听过那句话，这是一个数据的年代？搞不好几百年后，会有个很火的游戏叫《数据时代》。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;谷歌是一个数据就是一切的公司，搜索引擎只是一个外在的不能再外在的表面。公司的模式是，通过整合用户搜索的数据和信息，扩展自己的产品模式，加以包装，再以免费的方式出售给用户来换取更多数据。可以这样理解，我们每一个人都是谷歌的产品，通过出售我们，拿下巨额广告费。不知不觉中，我们就作为产品被谷歌卖了。虽然感觉不爽，但是，谷歌作为目前市值最高的公司，在全方面融入我们生活的情况下，依然没有赚过我们一分钱（这个论点可能快说不通了， 毕竟谷歌也出了不少硬件。当然，主要收入还是广告）。所以，结论是：他很牛，让他随便卖吧。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;讲谷歌就是因为想讲他的机器学习和人工智能，毕竟做为这个星球上的科技老大，很多科技走向的标杆还是他来树立的。在今年的Google I/O上，谷歌毫无保留的秀了很多新科技，这些科技的背后支撑就是机器学习和人工智能。可以说，这是一个在机器学习以及人工智能领域的小进步，真正的把机器学习和人工智能带到了我们能看得见摸得到的面前。科技可以有很多种方式来服务用户，机器学习和人工智能很多时候的作用用户是感受不到的。比如过滤垃圾邮件，推荐电影或者歌曲，无线网络的无缝转换等等，这些是低调的呈现。又比如高调到爆的阿尔法狗，直接干沉李世石。前者和后者都是科技，只是呈现的方式不一样而已。 貌似前者来的更高端上档次点，所谓“好的科技是让人感受不到科技的存在”。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;差点讲跑题，总喜欢讲讲几个科技大佬之间的故事，看来需要下次从新讲。那么，机器学习和人工智能的未来在哪里？简单概括，很深很深。电影里面总喜欢讲人工智能有一天会反人类，这貌似离谱，却符合很多逻辑。人类往往重视外在而忽略内在。同样的道理，人工智能不需要一个物理机器人来做事情，当数据和软件在彻底渗入我们生活的每一刻的时候，威胁也在滋生。在硬件为软件服务的今天，其间隔小于零。也许，电影里面的很多非现实正在现实中靠近。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;当然，我们不能带有悲观的态度看问题，这样科技就不会进步了。一个不恰当的例子就是，如同汽车带来便利的同时，也有相当大的危险性。主要问题是需要一个相当完善并且持续更新的体系来预防可能发生一切。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;如果往今后几年看的话，很明显，大量机器学习和人工智能相关的工作会出现。最先出现的就是各种人工智能的助手， 语音是首打。这些助手会通过用户的资料和使用习惯来学习用户的日常所需，一点一点的变聪明，一点一点变好用，从而替代生活中的琐事。简单预测，将来语音助手会像手机一样和我们的生活密不可分。语音助手成熟之后，同步翻译还会远吗？&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;在不久的将来，大批的简单单一的工作会被人工智能取代，好处是高效率以及小于人类万分之一的犯错几率。人类的工作重心则会移到更加人性话的一面，比如，服务，设计，情感等方面的工作。不用担心就业不足的问题，随着时代改变应运而生的这个时代所需的新工作机会。然而，时代推动的则是科技的改变。最后，套用一句诺基亚的广告词，“科技，以人为本”。&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
<category term="machine learning" />
<category term="AI" />
<category term="VR" />
<summary>机器学习，人工智能， 虚拟现实绝对是当下科技行业最火的三个话题。传统科技巨头们在这三个方面的投资已不是未知，回报颇丰。我觉得从发展前景，应用性和可塑造性几个方面来讲的话，虚拟现实目前还比不上机器学习和人工智能。所以，今天先不讨论虚拟现实（另外，苹果目前还没有虚拟现实的任何产品传闻，这太蹊跷，必有问题。所以，期待WWDC 2016）。</summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title>Starting ML</title>
<link href="http://localhost:3000/Machine-Learning/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Starting ML" />
<published>2016-06-01T00:00:00-06:00</published>
<updated>2016-06-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
<id>http://localhost:3000/Machine-Learning</id>
<content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:3000/Machine-Learning/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/yifanchen/ML&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;ML&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
<category term="Projects" />
<category term="Machine Learning" />
<summary>ML</summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title>The Silly Side Projects</title>
<link href="http://localhost:3000/silly-side-projects/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Silly Side Projects" />
<published>2016-05-26T00:00:00-06:00</published>
<updated>2016-05-26T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
<id>http://localhost:3000/silly-side-projects</id>
<content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:3000/silly-side-projects/">&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-silly-side-projects&quot;&gt;The silly side projects&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I never liked doing side projects for some reasons. It bugs me how passive I am when it comes to building projects outside of work. As developers, doing challenging projects outside of comfort zone is one of the most efficient and effective ways to get better. All of my friends and colleagues have been showing me their sweet paid side projects and the learning progress they have made by working on them. Like it or not, it is quite appealing to me. But, for some reasons, I just don’t find working on side projects rewarding at all. I hate to admit that I let my laziness drive me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Overjustification_effect&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Overjustification effect&lt;/a&gt;, meaning &lt;em&gt;an expected external incentive such as money or prizes decreases a person’s intrinsic motivation to perform a task&lt;/em&gt;. It is the exact reason why I don’t like doing side projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With overjustification effect in mind, I tend to work on something with no incentives and requirements at all. And intentionally, I made my first few side projects as simple, as silly as possible. The result of it is, I learned how my mindset works and how can I be motivated with this mentality. More importantly, knowledge gainning is the best reward to me.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
<category term="code" />
<category term="thoughts" />
<category term="side projects" />
<summary>The silly side projects</summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title>The Future of Mac Gaming</title>
<link href="http://localhost:3000/the-future-of-mac-gaming/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Future of Mac Gaming" />
<published>2016-05-21T00:00:00-06:00</published>
<updated>2016-05-21T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
<id>http://localhost:3000/the-future-of-mac-gaming</id>
<content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:3000/the-future-of-mac-gaming/">&lt;h3 id=&quot;mac-gaming-is-coming&quot;&gt;Mac gaming is coming&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For years, Mac gaming has only been a concept. With very limited development progress of OpenGL, Apple indeed needs its graphic technology to move away from OpenGL madness. &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/metal/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Metal&lt;/a&gt;, Apple’s graphic technology, was created to solve the problem. It reduces layers between graphic card and graphic APIs, providing developers a rich environment to work with. Performance wise, Apple promises that Metal can improve more than 50%. Now, Metal has been adopted widely on iOS for two years, and the result is satisfactory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_p8AsQhaVKI&quot;&gt;WWDC 2015&lt;/a&gt;, Apple announced that Metal is coming to El Captian. At the same time, Blizzard officially commented that Metal is already working internally on &lt;em&gt;World of Warcraft&lt;/em&gt;. Furthermore, it will be released by the end of the year. On top of this, &lt;em&gt;Starcraft 2&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Heros of the storm&lt;/em&gt; are expected to follow shortly after.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Metal, as a graphic API may not be able to revolutionize gaming on OSX. However, it cuts off the gap between Mac gaming and PC gaming significantly. Experiencing the same or better gaming experience on Mac just as on PC is not far anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reference: Here is a pretty good article I found, it talks about graphic APIs in depth:
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.insidemacgames.com/forum/index.php?showtopic=47801&quot; target=&quot;_blnak&quot;&gt;OS X Graphics API’s: OpenGL vs Metal vs Vulkan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
<category term="Mac Gaming" />
<category term="Technology" />
<category term="Metal" />
<summary>Mac gaming is coming</summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title>Google I/O 2016</title>
<link href="http://localhost:3000/google-io-2016/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Google I/O 2016" />
<published>2016-05-19T00:00:00-06:00</published>
<updated>2016-05-19T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
<id>http://localhost:3000/google-io-2016</id>
<content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:3000/google-io-2016/">&lt;h3 id=&quot;google-io&quot;&gt;Google I/O&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year’s Google I/O was hosted outdoors at Shoreline Amitheater, Mountain View, California. The weather has been lovely for its annual technology and developer conference. Google indeed introduced lots new products and technologies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;vr---virtual-reality&quot;&gt;VR - Virtual Reality&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s called Daydream. It is Google’s virtual reality platform. It comes with Android N. And man; it sounds exciting, VR on mobile, it is breathtaking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Undoubtedly, VR is the biggest thing today. As a tech company, if you aren’t planning to do something with VR or at least mention it in your conference, shame on you. Strangely, both Apple and Amazon haven’t had any VR product rumors yet. I can’t wait to see if Apple is going to introduce something cool at upcoming WWDC 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;android-wear-20&quot;&gt;Android Wear 2.0&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One feature makes Android Wear 2.0 better than WatchOS is its standalone OS. Without having any nearby Android phone, even with your phone turned off, you can send an email, respond a message and listen to music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;google-home&quot;&gt;Google Home&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google Home is Google’s voice assistant; it is finally here after Siri, Cortana and Echo. If you have seen Amazon Echo, Google Home will be very familiar to you. It is a physical voice assistant that helps people’s information needs and task management. With Google’s integration of gamil, calendar, search, etc., replacing Amazon Echo is just a time matter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;android-n&quot;&gt;Android N&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Android N, still needs to be named, is the new Android OS. Google claims that it will improve performance, security and productivity from Marshmallow. Android N is officially supporting Vulkan, which is a relatively new graphic technology that is slowly replacing OpenGL. As same as Metal, Apple’s graphic technology introduced at WWDC 2014, both of them offer APIs that allow developers to work with graphic card directly. Simply put, Android N is going to bring better and richer gaming experience. More importantly, it is making a concrete foundation for Virtual Reality in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;allo-and-duo&quot;&gt;Allo and Duo&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google, once again is trying to emulate social media. Both Allo and Duo are making a better messaging experience. Allo is specializing in chat, comparing Facebook Messenger, it offers lots more features. Machine Learning and AI make Allo the smartest chat app ever, image processing and search integration allow users to do things without leaving Allo. Duo, a Facetime competitor, giving a feature called Knock Knock, allow users to see a short video of callers before answering it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;android-studio-20&quot;&gt;Android Studio 2.0&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google intends to build an excellent IDE to replace Eclipse, and the result is Android Studio. Android Studio 2.0 comes with sweet Instant Run features, offers a fast and feature-rich emulator, and robust and flexible build system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;amp&quot;&gt;AMP&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AMP is Accelerated Mobile Pages, &lt;em&gt;a open source initiative that embodies the vision that publishers can create mobile optimized content once and have it load instantly everywhere.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google claims AMP is going to be the next generation of static page builder, one feature worthy mentioning is the “almost instant rendering”. This could mean that the pursuit of AMP has been pure and straightforward - rendering speed. As in today, mobile device is taking majority of the web traffic, rendering speed is no longer an optimization in the first place, instead, it’s a key factor directly outputs the right technology to use. And the result of it has always been that the user
experience a richer content with a incredible rendering speed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google I/O 2016 brought us many surprises, and it also unveiled the roadmap of Google for the next year. Machine Learning and Artificial Intelligence have been leading roles in this conference; both of them are getting more and more irreplaceable to have technology serving people in a perfect way. As I have mentioned, no matter how advanced technology is, the best technology has always been imperceptible and seemingly nonexistent.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
<category term="Google i/o" />
<category term="Technology" />
<summary>Google I/O</summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title>关于美队3 - 内战</title>
<link href="http://localhost:3000/about-captain-america-civil-war/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="关于美队3 - 内战" />
<published>2016-05-17T00:00:00-06:00</published>
<updated>2016-05-17T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
<id>http://localhost:3000/about-captain-america-civil-war</id>
<content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:3000/about-captain-america-civil-war/">&lt;h3 id=&quot;section&quot;&gt;关于美队3&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;美队3 －内战毫无疑问是美队三部曲里面最好看的一部，每个人物的塑造都异常饱满，选择站边的原因也非常有说服力。很多人在争论到底哪边是正确的，这些其实都是无力的争议，电影本身已经给了很充足的理由为什么每个人会做出不同的选择，结合每个角色的过去和之前的经历，其实根本没有站边的必要。 欣赏和理解角色的同时，了解角色的性格会让电影更出彩。我本来是带着倾向于铁人一边的心情去看的，看过之后，我无法选择站在哪一边。这也是为什么电影好看的主要原因之一，让我的期待以及希望被电影内容的带入而改变。人物的选择其实就是政治选择， 无对无错，只是每个人相信的方式不一样而已。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;有位智者曾经说过：你不是神，无论你做什么，总会有不喜欢你的人。&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
<category term="Captain America" />
<category term="Film Review" />
<summary>关于美队3</summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title>关于签证</title>
<link href="http://localhost:3000/about-visa/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="关于签证" />
<published>2016-05-06T00:00:00-06:00</published>
<updated>2016-05-06T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
<id>http://localhost:3000/about-visa</id>
<content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:3000/about-visa/">&lt;p&gt;爆宝地段，连刷3年，至少给个灵魂奖励一下。没有关系，拿出激情接着刷，人品爆发的节奏正在靠近。借用《火星救援》里的一句台词：“I’m fucked, but I’m not giving up.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
<category term="visa" />
<category term="H1B" />
<summary>爆宝地段，连刷3年，至少给个灵魂奖励一下。没有关系，拿出激情接着刷，人品爆发的节奏正在靠近。借用《火星救援》里的一句台词：“I’m fucked, but I’m not giving up.”</summary>
</entry>
<entry>
<title>Two Weeks of Neovim</title>
<link href="http://localhost:3000/two-weeks-of-neovim/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Two Weeks of Neovim" />
<published>2016-05-02T00:00:00-06:00</published>
<updated>2016-05-02T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
<id>http://localhost:3000/two-weeks-of-neovim</id>
<content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:3000/two-weeks-of-neovim/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;two-weeks-down-for-neovim&quot;&gt;Two weeks down for Neovim&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wrote a post about switching to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cyfyifanchen.com/first-day-of-neovim/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Neovim&lt;/a&gt; a couple of weeks ago. Now, I am writing another post confirming it was a wise choice. Unlike others, I haven’t felt buggy at all in my two weeks of full time use. In return, the speed of Neovim is the best reward to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those who are currently struggling speed of MacVim or Gvim, I would strongly suggest you consider switching. Neovim is newer with a lot less lines of code to maintain. For developers who switched, feedbacks are all positive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is my &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/yifanchen/dotfiles/blob/master/.vimrc&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.vimrc&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, all the Plugins and settings are compatible with Neovim. Use it as a reference if you are considering switch.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
<category term="vim" />
<category term="Neovim" />
<category term="thoughts" />
<summary>Two weeks down for Neovim</summary>
</entry>
</feed>
